<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 3/2/2016 4:32:36 PM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_ko_KR>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROJECT_PUBLIC_WORKS">
			<Text>공공 사업</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROJECT_PUBLIC_WORKS_HELP">
			<Text>도시의 [ICON_HAPPINESS_1]행복이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 증가하고 전역 [ICON_HAPPINESS_1]행복 요구 수치가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]10%[ENDCOLOR] 감소합니다. 도시의 [ICON_FOOD]/[ICON_PRODUCTION]곤경, [ICON_GOLD]빈곤, [ICON_RESEARCH]문맹, [ICON_CULTURE]무료, [ICON_PEACE]종교 분쟁에서 오는 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]15%[ENDCOLOR] 감소합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]반복 가능한 프로젝트이지만 시대마다 [ICON_PRODUCTION]생산 비용이 [COLOR_NEGATIVE_TEXT]100[ICON_PRODUCTION][ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. 프로젝트를 수행할 때마다 [ICON_PRODUCTION]생산 비용이 [COLOR_NEGATIVE_TEXT]100[ICON_PRODUCTION][ENDCOLOR] 증가하고 [ICON_GOLD]유지비가 [COLOR_NEGATIVE_TEXT]2[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROJECT_PUBLIC_WORKS_PEDIA">
			<Text>Public works are a broad category of infrastructure projects, financed and constructed by the government, for recreational, employment, and health and safety uses in the greater community. They include public buildings (municipal buildings, schools, hospitals), transport infrastructure (roads, railroads, bridges, pipelines, canals, ports, airports), public spaces (public squares, parks, beaches), public services (water supply and treatment, sewage treatment, electrical grid, dams), and other, usually long-term, physical assets and facilities. Though often interchangeable with public infrastructure and public capital, public works does not necessarily carry an economic component, thereby being a broader term.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROJECT_PUBLIC_WORKS_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Construct this Project in cities that are suffering from chronic [ICON_HAPPINESS_3] Unhappiness caused by Needs, and you have run out options to deal with it. Watch out, however, as this project becomes more expensive to build every time you construct it in this City, and it costs Gold to upkeep. Use this as a last resort, not as a first solution, when dealing with Unhappiness from Needs.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_THEMING_BONUS_ROYAL_LIBRARY">
			<Text>전 세계에서 온 지식</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ROYAL_LIBRARY_THEMING_BONUS_HELP">
			<Text>보너스를 극대화 하려면 모든 걸작 슬롯을 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]다른 문명[ENDCOLOR]이 만든 [COLOR_YELLOW]문학[ENDCOLOR]으로 채우십시오.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CO_CITY_TOURISM_GA_BONUS">
			<Text>[ICON_BULLET][COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]+{1_Num}[ENDCOLOR] [ICON_TOURISM]  수도 [ICON_CULTURE]문화의 {2_Num}%에서 획득</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_RIALTO_DISTRICT">
			<Text>리알토 지구</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDING_RIALTO_DISTRICT_TEXT">
			<Text> The Rialto is and has been for many centuries the financial and commercial centre of Venice. It is an area of the San Polo sestiere of Venice, Italy, also known for its markets and for the Rialto Bridge across the Grand Canal. The area was settled by the ninth century, when a small area in the middle of the Realtine Islands on either side of the Rio Businiacus was known as the Rivoaltus, or "high bank". Eventually the Businiacus became known as the Grand Canal, and the district the Rialto, referring only to the area on the left bank.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_RIALTO_DISTRICT_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Unique Venetian building, only buildable in Venice's Capital. This building boosts the value of Trade Routes to and from the City, and generates 1 World Congress Delegate for every 100 Gold Per Turn that Venice produces, up to 25% of all City-States ever alive in the game (minimum of 1 Delegate). In addition, this building reduces the Gold cost of purchasing Units and Buildings in the City by 10%. Cannot be constructed if the Arsenale di Venezia or Murano Glassworks are present in the City.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_RIALTO_DISTRICT_HELP">
			<Text>베네치아의 고유 건물입니다. 모든 도시에서 [ICON_GOLD]골드로 유닛을 구매하거나 건물 건설에 투자하는 비용이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]10%[ENDCOLOR] [COLOR:105:105:105:255]([ICON_CAPITAL]수도는 15%)[ENDCOLOR] 감소합니다. 도시의 턴당 [ICON_GOLD]골드 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]100[ENDCOLOR]마다 세계 대회 추가 [COLOR_YELLOW]대표단[ENDCOLOR]을 1명 [COLOR:105:105:105:255](한도: 현존 모든 도시 국가 수의 [COLOR_NEGATIVE_TEXTTIVE_TEXT]25%[ENDCOLOR])[ENDCOLOR] 확보합니다. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]이 도시로 향하는 [ICON_INTERNATIONAL_TRADE]교역로마다 도시의 [ICON_GOLD]골드가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]3[ENDCOLOR] 증가하고 교역로를 개설한 상대 문명의 [ICON_GOLD]골드도 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]3[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]도시에 [COLOR_YELLOW]피아자 산 마르코[ENDCOLOR]가 있어야 건설할 수 있습니다. 도시에 [COLOR_NEGATIVE_TEXT]아스넬 디 베네치아[ENDCOLOR] 또는 [COLOR_NEGATIVE_TEXT]무라노 유리공방[ENDCOLOR]이 없어야 건설할 수 있습니다. 문명에 도시가 많을수록 건설에 필요한 [ICON_PRODUCTION]생산과 [ICON_CITIZEN]시민이 증가합니다. 이 불가사의는 문명당 하나만 건설할 수 있는 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]국가 불가사의[ENDCOLOR]입니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_VENETIAN_ARSENALE">
			<Text>아스넬 디 베네치아</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDING_VENETIAN_ARSENALE_TEXT">
			<Text>The Venetian Arsenal is a complex of former shipyards and armories clustered together in the city of Venice in northern Italy. Owned by the state, the Arsenal was responsible for the bulk of the Venetian republic's naval power during the middle part of the second millennium AD. It was one of the earliest large-scale industrial enterprises in history.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_VENETIAN_ARSENALE_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Unique Venetian building, only buildable in Venice's Capital. This building boosts Production, increases City Defense, increases Military Supply, and provides all Naval Units with the 'Venetian Craftsmanship' promotion, which increases Combat Strength and Movement. Cannot be constructed if the Rialto District or Murano Glassworks are present in the City.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_VENETIAN_ARSENALE_HELP">
			<Text>베네치아의 고유 건물입니다. 도시의 생산이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]15%[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. 군사 유닛의 보급 한도가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]5[ENDCOLOR] 증가하고, [ICON_CITIZEN]시민의 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]25%[ENDCOLOR]만큼 증가합니다. 모든 해상 유닛에 [COLOR_PLAYER_PURPLE]베네치아 공작술[ENDCOLOR] 승급을 부여합니다. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]도시에 [COLOR_YELLOW]피아자 산 마르코[ENDCOLOR]가 있어야 건설할 수 있습니다. 도시에 [COLOR_NEGATIVE_TEXT]리알토 지구[ENDCOLOR] 또는 [COLOR_NEGATIVE_TEXT]무라노 유리공방[ENDCOLOR]이 없어야 건설할 수 있습니다. 문명에 도시가 많을수록 건설에 필요한 [ICON_PRODUCTION]생산과 [ICON_CITIZEN]시민이 증가합니다. 이 불가사의는 문명당 하나만 건설할 수 있는 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]국가 불가사의[ENDCOLOR]입니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PIAZZA_SAN_MARCO">
			<Text>피아자 산 마르코</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDING_PIAZZA_SAN_MARCO_TEXT">
			<Text>Piazza San Marco (often known in English as St Mark's Square), is the principal public square of Venice, Italy, where it is generally known just as "the Piazza" (la Piazza). All other urban spaces in the city (except the Piazzetta and the Piazzale Roma) are called "campi" (fields). The Piazzetta (the 'little Piazza') is an extension of the Piazza towards the lagoon in its south east corner (see plan). The two spaces together form the social, religious and political centre of Venice and are commonly considered together.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PIAZZA_SAN_MARCO_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Unique Venetian building, replacing the National Monument. Eschews most National Monument abilities in favor of providing a small boost to City yields, a boost to the City's Great People rate, and the ability to ignore all Advanced Actions that can be performed by Spies. This means that your Capital is well-defended against the theft of Gold, Science, and other important resources. Unlocks access to Murano Glassworks, Arsenale di Venezia, and Rialto District once Guilds is researched. Only one of these buildings may be constructed per game.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PIAZZA_SAN_MARCO_HELP">
			<Text>국가 기념비를 대체하는 베네치아의 고유 건물입니다. 도시의 [ICON_GREAT_PEOPLE]위인 출현율이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]33%[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. 군사 유닛의 보급 한도가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]5[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. 적[ICON_SPY]스파이가 이 도시에서 고급 첩보 활동을 수행할 수 없습니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][COLOR_RESEARCH_STORED]길드[ENDCOLOR]를 연구하면 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]무라노 유리공방[ENDCOLOR], [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]아스넬 디 베네치아[ENDCOLOR], [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]리알토 지구[ENDCOLOR] 중 하나를 건설할 수 있습니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_CAPITAL][COLOR_YELLOW]수도[ENDCOLOR]에만 건설할 수 있습니다. 이 불가사의는 문명당 하나만 건설할 수 있는 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]국가 불가사의[ENDCOLOR]입니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MURANO_GLASSWORKS">
			<Text>무라노 유리공방</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDING_MURANO_GLASSWORKS_TEXT">
			<Text>Murano's reputation as a center for glassmaking was born when the Venetian Republic, fearing fire and the destruction of the city’s mostly wooden buildings, ordered glassmakers to move their foundries to Murano in 1291. Murano glass is still associated with Venetian glass. Murano's glassmakers were soon numbered among the island’s most prominent citizens. By the fourteenth century, glassmakers were allowed to wear swords, enjoyed immunity from prosecution by the Venetian state and found their daughters married into Venice’s most affluent families. While benefiting from certain statutory privileges, glassmakers were forbidden to leave the Republic. However, many of them took the risks associated with migration and established glass furnaces in surrounding cities and farther afield, even in England and the Netherlands.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MURANO_GLASSWORKS_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Unique Venetian building, only buildable in Venice's Capital. Boosts the value of Great Person Improvements and Villages for all Cities, and provides two Art/Artifact slots. Construct this building if you are pursuing a Cultural Victory. Cannot be constructed if the Arsenale di Venezia or Rialto District are present in the City.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MURANO_GLASSWORKS_HELP">
			<Text>베네치아의 고유 건물입니다. 모든 [ICON_GREAT_PEOPLE]위인 시설 및 마을의 [ICON_FOOD]식량 및 [ICON_TOURISM]관광이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]2[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [ICON_GREAT_WORK]걸작 예술품 슬롯 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]2개[ENDCOLOR]를 포함합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]테마보너스:  [ICON_RESEARCH]과학 +5[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]도시에 [COLOR_YELLOW]피아자 산 마르코[ENDCOLOR]가 있어야 건설할 수 있습니다.도시에 [COLOR_NEGATIVE_TEXT]리알토 지구[ENDCOLOR] 또는 [COLOR_NEGATIVE_TEXT]아스날 디 베네치아[ENDCOLOR]가 없어야 건설할 수 있습니다. 문명에 도시가 많을수록 건설에 필요한 [ICON_PRODUCTION]생산과 [ICON_CITIZEN]시민이 증가합니다. 이 불가사의는 문명당 하나만 건설할 수 있는 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]국가 불가사의[ENDCOLOR]입니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MURANO_GLASSWORKS_THEMING_BONUS_HELP">
			<Text>보너스를 극대화 하려면 모든 걸작 슬롯을 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]건물 소유자[ENDCOLOR]가 만든 [COLOR_YELLOW]예술품[ENDCOLOR]으로 채우십시오.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_THEMING_BONUS_MURANO_GLASSWORKS">
			<Text>무라노 명작 컬렉션</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TRAINSTATION">
			<Text>철도역</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_TRAINSTATION_TEXT">
			<Text>A train station, railway station, railroad station, or depot (see below) is a railway facility where trains regularly stop to load or unload passengers or freight. It generally consists of at least one track-side platform and a station building (depot) providing such ancillary services as ticket sales and waiting rooms. If a station is on a single-track line, it often has a passing loop to facilitate traffic movements. The smallest stations are most often referred to as "stops" or, in some parts of the world, as "halts" (flag stops). Stations may be at ground level, underground, or elevated. Connections may be available to intersecting rail lines or other transport modes such as buses, trams or other rapid transit systems.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TRAINSTATION_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Provides a massive boost to City Production and Gold during the Industrial Era. Requires a direct Railroad connection, with railroad tiles, to the Capital (Harbor connections do not count!) before it can be constructed, so you need to invest in your Railroad infrastructure before you can reap the benefits of this building! Cannot be built in the same City as a Seaport.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TRAINSTATION_HELP">
			<Text>이 도시에서 출발하는 국내 [ICON_TURNS_REMAINING]교역로의 [ICON_FOOD]식량이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]6[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_CAPITAL]수도와 [COLOR_YELLOW]철도로 [ICON_CITY_CONNECTED]연결된 도시[ENDCOLOR]에만 건설할 수 있습니다. [ICON_RES_COAL]석탄 [COLOR_NEGATIVE_TEXT]1개[ENDCOLOR]가 필요합니다. 도시에 [COLOR_NEGATIVE_TEXT]항구[ENDCOLOR]가 없어야 건설할 수 있습니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_THEMING_BONUS_BROADCAST_TOWER_NATIONAL">
			<Text>KCIV 101.5FM - #1 클래식 JAM</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_THEMING_BONUS_BROADCAST_TOWER_CLASSICS">
			<Text>KSID 107.7FM - 오늘의 히트 곡, 어제의 명곡</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_THEMING_BONUS_BROADCAST_TOWER_ALL">
			<Text>KGAZ 89.5FM - 일렉트릭 라디오 믹스</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BROADCAST_TOWER_THEMING_BONUS_HELP">
			<Text>보너스를 극대화 하려면 두 걸작이 다음 기준 중 하나를 충족하는지 확인하십시오.[NEWLINE]1.) 모두 같은 시대 [NEWLINE]2.) 모두 다른 시대[NEWLINE]3.) 모두 연속된 시대</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SKOLA">
			<Text>스콜라</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_SKOLA_TEXT">
			<Text>Swedish state schools are funded by tax money. This goes for both primary and secondary school (Swedish: grundskola), high school (Swedish: gymnasium) and universities. When studying at a university, however, you might have to pay for accommodation and literature. There are private schools as well who also receive funding from the government, but they may charge a fee from the parents.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Compulsory education starts at seven years of age, with an optional year in förskola (pre-school). The Swedish primary school is split into three parts; Lågstadiet – “the low stage”, which covers grades 1 to 3. This is where you learn the basics of the three main subjects – in Swedish called kärnämnen – Swedish, English and mathematics. It also includes some natural science. Mellanstadiet – “the middle stage”, which covers grades 4 to 6, introduces the children to more detailed subjects. Woodwork and needlework, social and domestic science, and even a second, foreign language in grade 6, a B-språk (B-language). The languages available are usually French, Spanish or German depending on the school. Högstadiet, “the high stage”, is the last stage of the compulsory education, between grades 7 and 9. This is when studies get more in-depth and are taken to an international level.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Swedish children take national exams at grades 3, 6 and 9. Children at grade 3 take these exams in two of the three main subjects: Swedish and mathematics. In grade 5 the exams extend to the third main subject, English, and in grade 9 the exams also extend to natural science, foreign languages, and one of the four subjects in "Samhällsorientering" (geography, history, religious studies, and civics). They first receive grades in grade 6. The grading system is letter-based, ranging from A-F, where F is the lowest grade and A is the highest. F means "not approved", while all other ratings above F mean "approved". There are only objectives for E, C and A; D means the person has met most (but not all) objectives for C, while B means the person has met most objectives for A. When applying to gymnasium (high schools) or universities, a meritvärde (“meritous point value”) is calculated. E is worth 10 points, D 12.5 points, C 15 points, and so on. Children not being approved in Swedish, English and mathematics will have to study at a special high school program called the “individual program”. Once they are approved, they may apply to an ordinary high school program. Swedes study at high school for three years, between the ages of 16 and 18.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SKOLA_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Unique Swedish replacement for the Public School. This building is cheaper, more effective, and costs less maintenance than the building it replaces, and also boosts the city's [ICON_CULTURE] Culture.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SKOLA_HELP">
			<Text>공립학교를 대체하는 스웨덴의 고유 건물입니다. 도시에서 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]고고학자[ENDCOLOR]를 생산할 수 있습니다. [ICON_CITIZEN]시민 3명마다 [ICON_CULTURE]문화가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 증가하고 [ICON_CITIZEN]시민 1명마다 [ICON_RESEARCH]과학이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [ICON_RESEARCH]문맹에서 오는 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 감소합니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BASILICA_DESC">
			<Text>바실리카</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_BASILICA_TEXT">
			<Text>The Latin word basilica, has three distinct applications in modern English. The word was originally used to describe an open, Roman, public court building, usually located adjacent to the forum of a Roman town. By extension it was applied to Christian buildings of the same form and continues to be used in an architectural sense to describe those buildings with a central nave and aisles. Later, the term came to refer specifically to a large and important church that has been given special ceremonial rights by the Pope.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BASILICA_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Unique Byzantine replacement for the Temple. This building does not require maintenance, boosts the city's [ICON_PEACE] Faith output based on the number of [ICON_CITIZEN] Citizens in the city, and doubles Religious Pressure generated by Trade Routes.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BASILICA_HELP">
			<Text>사원을 대체하는 비잔틴의 고유 건물입니다. [ICON_CITIZEN]시민 3명마다 [ICON_PEACE]신앙이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [ICON_GREAT_WORK]걸작 음악 슬롯 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1개[ENDCOLOR]를 포함합니다. [ICON_PEACE]종교 분쟁에서 오는 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 감소합니다. 도시의 [ICON_RELIGION]종교 압력이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]25%[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [ICON_INTERNATIONAL_TRADE] 교역로가 제공하는 종교 압력이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]두 배[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_RES_INCENSE] 향: [ICON_CULTURE]문화 +1 [ICON_GOLD]골드 +1[NEWLINE][ICON_RES_WINE] 와인: [ICON_CULTURE]문화 +1 [ICON_GOLD]골드 +1</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GREAT_COTHON">
			<Text>코톤</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GREAT_COTHON_PEDIA">
			<Text>A cothon is an artificial, protected inner harbor such as that in Carthage during the Punic Wars around 200 BC. The cothon at Carthage was divided into a rectangular merchant harbor followed by an inner protected harbor reserved for military use only. This inner harbor was circular and surrounded by an outer ring of structures divided into a series of docking bays for ship maintenance, along with an island structure at its centre that also housed navy ships. Each individual docking bay featured a raised slipway. Above the raised docking bays was a second level consisting of warehouses where oars and rigging were kept along with supplies such as wood and canvas. On the island structure there existed a raised 'cabin' where the admiral in command could observe the whole harbor along with the surrounding sea. Altogether the inner docking complex could house up to 220 ships. The entire harbor was protected by an outer wall and the main entrance could be closed off with iron chains.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GREAT_COTHON_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Unique Carthaginian replacement for the East India Company. Must have built a Market in the city. In addition to the normal bonuses provided by the East India Company, the Great Cothon provides additional gold for both recipient and target of trade routes from the city where it is built, and two additional trade routes. All Harbors in your empire also gain +3 Production, and all Lighthouses gain +2 Culture. Unlike the East India Company, the Great Cothon is made available in the Classical Era with the discovery of Currency.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GREAT_COTHON_HELP">
			<Text>동인도 회사를 대체하는 카르타고의 고유 건물입니다. 이 도시의 모든 사치 자원을 추가로 한 개씩 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]복제[ENDCOLOR]합니다. 이 도시로 향하는 [ICON_INTERNATIONAL_TRADE]교역로마다 도시의 [ICON_GOLD]골드가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]5[ENDCOLOR] 증가하고 교역로를 개설한 상대 문명의 [ICON_GOLD]골드도 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]3[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_INTERNATIONAL_TRADE]교역로의 자원 다양성 수치가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]25%[ENDCOLOR] [COLOR:105:105:105:255](양수일 때)[ENDCOLOR] 증가하거나 [COLOR_NEGATIVE_TEXT]25%[ENDCOLOR] [COLOR:105:105:105:255](음수일 때)[ENDCOLOR] 감소합니다. 추가 [ICON_INTERNATIONAL_TRADE]교역로를 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]2개[ENDCOLOR] 제공합니다. 모든 항만의 [ICON_PRODUCTION]생산이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]3[ENDCOLOR] 증가하고, 모든 등대의 [ICON_CULTURE]문화가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]2[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [ICON_GOLD]빈곤에서 오는 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 감소합니다. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]도시에 [COLOR_YELLOW]세관[ENDCOLOR]이 있어야 건설할 수 있습니다. 문명에 도시가 많을수록 건설에 필요한 [ICON_PRODUCTION]생산과 [ICON_CITIZEN]시민이 증가합니다. 이 불가사의는 문명당 하나만 건설할 수 있는 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]국가 불가사의[ENDCOLOR]입니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MAUSOLEUM_HELP">
			<Text>적 유닛을 처치할 때 [ICON_PEACE]신앙을 [COLOR:105:105:105:255](시대별 보정)[ENDCOLOR] 제공합니다. 모든 성지의 [ICON_PEACE]신앙이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]5[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [ICON_PEACE]종교 분쟁에서 오는 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행이 감소하고, [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT개혁 교리[ENDCOLOR]를 선택할 수 있습니다. 도시의 [ICON_RELIGION]종교 압력이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]25%[ENDCOLOR] 증가하고 개종에 대한 도시의 저항이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]10%[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE][COLOR_YELLOW]성도[ENDCOLOR]에만 건설할 수 있습니다. 전 세계에 당신 문명의 종교를 따르는 신도 수가 적어도 15% 이상 있어야 합니다. 이 불가사의는 문명당 하나만 건설할 수 있는 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]국가 불가사의[ENDCOLOR]입니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MAUSOLEUM">
			<Text>마우솔레움</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MAUSOLEUM_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Build the Mausoleum to gain [ICON_PEACE] Faith from casualties in war and to improve all Holy Sites. Constructing this National Wonder will also allow you to choose a Reformation Belief. May only be constructed in a Holy City, and only if at least 15% of the global population follows your Religion (scaling with map size).</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MAUSOLEUM_TEXT">
			<Text>A mausoleum is an external free-standing building constructed as a monument enclosing the interment space or burial chamber of a deceased person or people. A monument without the interment is a cenotaph. A mausoleum may be considered a type of tomb, or the tomb may be considered to be within the mausoleum. A Christian mausoleum sometimes includes a chapel.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HEAVENLY_THRONE_HELP">
			<Text>모든 성지의 [ICON_PEACE]신앙이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]5[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [ICON_PEACE]종교 분쟁에서 오는 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행이 감소하고, [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT개혁 교리[ENDCOLOR]를 선택할 수 있습니다. 도시의 [ICON_RELIGION]종교 압력이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]25%[ENDCOLOR] 증가하고 개종에 대한 도시의 저항이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]10%[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][COLOR_YELLOW]성도[ENDCOLOR]에만 건설할 수 있습니다. 전 세계에 당신 문명의 종교를 따르는 신도 수가 적어도 15% 이상 있어야 합니다. 이 불가사의는 문명당 하나만 건설할 수 있는 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]국가 불가사의[ENDCOLOR]입니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HEAVENLY_THRONE">
			<Text>천상의 옥좌</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HEAVENLY_THRONE_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Build the Celestial Throne for a big boost to your Holy City's base yields and to improve all Holy Sites. Constructing this National Wonder will also allow you to choose a Reformation Belief. May only be constructed in a Holy City, and only if at least 15% of the global population follows your Religion (scaling with map size). Reduces [ICON_HAPPINESS_3] Religious Unrest, and allows you to select a Reformation Belief.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HEAVENLY_THRONE_TEXT">
			<Text>A throne is the seat of state of a potentate or dignitary, especially the seat occupied by a sovereign on state occasions; or the seat occupied by a pope or bishop on ceremonial occasions. "Throne" in an abstract sense can also refer to the monarchy or the Crown itself, an instance of metonymy, and is also used in many expressions such as "the power behind the throne".</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GREAT_ALTAR_HELP">
			<Text>군사 유닛을 생산할 때 [ICON_PRODUCTION]생산 보너스를 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]15%[ENDCOLOR] 제공합니다. 모든 성지의 [ICON_PRODUCTION]생산이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]5[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [ICON_PEACE]종교 분쟁에서 오는 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행이 감소하고, [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT개혁 교리[ENDCOLOR]를 선택할 수 있습니다. 도시의 [ICON_RELIGION]종교 압력이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]25%[ENDCOLOR] 증가하고 개종에 대한 도시의 저항이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]10%[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][COLOR_YELLOW]성도[ENDCOLOR]에만 건설할 수 있습니다. 전 세계에 당신 문명의 종교를 따르는 신도 수가 적어도 15% 이상 있어야 합니다. 이 불가사의는 문명당 하나만 건설할 수 있는 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]국가 불가사의[ENDCOLOR]입니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GREAT_ALTAR">
			<Text>위대한 제단</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GREAT_ALTAR_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Build the Great Altar for a boost to Military Unit production and to improve all Holy Sites. Constructing this National Wonder will also allow you to choose a Reformation Belief. May only be constructed in a Holy City, and only if at least 15% of the global population follows your Religion (scaling with map size). Reduces [ICON_HAPPINESS_3] Religious Unrest, and allows you to select a Reformation Belief.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GREAT_ALTAR_TEXT">
			<Text>An altar is any structure upon which offerings such as sacrifices are made for religious purposes. Altars are usually found at shrines, and they can be located in temples, churches and other places of worship. Today they are used particularly in Christianity, Buddhism, Hinduism, Shinto, Taoism, as well as in Neopaganism and Ceremonial Magic. Judaism used such a structure until the destruction of the Second Temple. Many historical faiths also made use of them, including Greek and Norse religion.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_RELIQUARY_HELP">
			<Text>모든 성지의 [ICON_TOURISM]관광이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]5[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [ICON_GREAT_WORK]걸작 예술품 슬롯 4개를 포함합니다. [ICON_PEACE]종교 분쟁에서 오는 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행이 감소하고, [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT개혁 교리[ENDCOLOR]를 선택할 수 있습니다. 도시의 [ICON_RELIGION]종교 압력이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]25%[ENDCOLOR] 증가하고 개종에 대한 도시의 저항이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]10%[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]테마보너스:  [ICON_PEACE]신앙 +10[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][COLOR_YELLOW]성도[ENDCOLOR]에만 건설할 수 있습니다. 전 세계에 당신 문명의 종교를 따르는 신도 수가 적어도 15% 이상 있어야 합니다. 이 불가사의는 문명당 하나만 건설할 수 있는 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]국가 불가사의[ENDCOLOR]입니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_RELIQUARY">
			<Text>성유물함</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_RELIQUARY_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Build the Reliquary for a powerful Tourism-centric bonus and bonuses for all Holy Sites. The building's Tourism bonus is only possible if all four Works of Art/Artifacts come from differing players. Constructing this National Wonder will also allow you to choose a Reformation Belief. May only be constructed in a Holy City, and only if at least 15% of the global population follows your Religion (scaling with map size). Reduces [ICON_HAPPINESS_3] Religious Unrest, and allows you to select a Reformation Belief.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_RELIQUARY_TEXT">
			<Text>A reliquary is a container for relics. These may be the purported physical remains of saints, such as bones, pieces of clothing, or some object associated with saints or other religious figures. The authenticity of any given relic is often a matter of debate; for that reason, some churches require documentation of the relic's provenance. Relics have long been important to Buddhists, Christians, Hindus and many other religions. In these cultures, reliquaries are often presented in shrines, churches, or temples to which the faithful make pilgrimages in order to gain blessings. In Central West Africa, reliquaries used in the Bwete rituals contain objects considered magical, or the bones of ancestors, and are commonly constructed with a guardian figure attached to the reliquary.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_THEMING_BONUS_RELIQUARY_HELP">
			<Text>보너스를 극대화 하려면 모든 걸작 슬롯을 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]다른 문명[ENDCOLOR]이 만든 [COLOR_YELLOW]유물 또는 예술품[ENDCOLOR]으로 채우십시오.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_THEMING_BONUS_RELIQUARY">
			<Text>{2_CivAdjective} 성유물함</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DIVINE_COURT_HELP">
			<Text>모든 성지의 [ICON_GOLD]골드가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]5[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다.[ICON_PEACE]종교 분쟁에서 오는 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행이 감소하고, [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT개혁 교리[ENDCOLOR]를 선택할 수 있습니다. 도시의 [ICON_RELIGION]종교 압력이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]25%[ENDCOLOR] 증가하고 개종에 대한 도시의 저항이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]10%[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][COLOR_YELLOW]성도[ENDCOLOR]에만 건설할 수 있습니다. 전 세계에 당신 문명의 종교를 따르는 신도 수가 적어도 15% 이상 있어야 합니다. 이 불가사의는 문명당 하나만 건설할 수 있는 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]국가 불가사의[ENDCOLOR]입니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DIVINE_COURT">
			<Text>성스러운 법정</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DIVINE_COURT_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Build the Divine Court for a boost to Gold output and to improve all Holy Sites. Constructing this National Wonder will also allow you to choose a Reformation Belief. May only be constructed in a Holy City, and only if at least 15% of the global population follows your Religion (scaling with map size). Reduces [ICON_HAPPINESS_3] Religious Unrest, and allows you to select a Reformation Belief.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DIVINE_COURT_TEXT">
			<Text>A beth din ("house of judgment," or divine court) is a rabbinical court of Judaism. In ancient times, it was the building block of the legal system in the Biblical Land of Israel. Today, it is invested with legal powers in a number of religious matters (din Torah, "matter of litigation," plural dinei Torah) both in Israel and in Jewish communities in the Diaspora, where its judgments hold varying degrees of authority (depending upon the jurisdiction and subject matter) in matters specifically related to Jewish religious life.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SACRED_GARDEN_HELP">
			<Text>모든 성지의 [ICON_FOOD]식량이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]5[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [ICON_PEACE]종교 분쟁에서 오는 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행이 감소하고, [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT개혁 교리[ENDCOLOR]를 선택할 수 있습니다. 도시의 [ICON_RELIGION]종교 압력이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]25%[ENDCOLOR] 증가하고 개종에 대한 도시의 저항이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]10%[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][COLOR_YELLOW]성도[ENDCOLOR]에만 건설할 수 있습니다. 전 세계에 당신 문명의 종교를 따르는 신도 수가 적어도 15% 이상 있어야 합니다. 이 불가사의는 문명당 하나만 건설할 수 있는 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]국가 불가사의[ENDCOLOR]입니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SACRED_GARDEN">
			<Text>신성한 정원</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SACRED_GARDEN_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Build the Sacred Garden for a boost to Culture output and to improve all Holy Sites. Constructing this National Wonder will also allow you to choose a Reformation Belief. May only be constructed in a Holy City, and only if at least 15% of the global population follows your Religion (scaling with map size). Reduces [ICON_HAPPINESS_3] Religious Unrest, and allows you to select a Reformation Belief.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SACRED_GARDEN_TEXT">
			<Text>Religion has been an important influence on garden design. Temple gardens were made in Mesopotamia and Ancient Egypt. Sacred groves were made in ancient India, Greece, Rome, China and Japan. Sacred trees were important in Celtic and Germanic Europe and still are important in India. Many groves or forests were sacred in ancient India and continue to be so in modern Hindu worship. Buddhism had a significant influence on garden design, with the Zen gardens of China and Japan as famous examples. In Christianity, particularly Catholicism and Anglicanism, Mary gardens are common among churches and institutions. The practise of creating sacred gardens is re-invigorated and adapted for modern times in the Ringing Cedars Series of books by Russian author Vladimir Megre.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HOLY_COUNCIL_HELP">
			<Text>모든 성지의 [ICON_RESEARCH]과학이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]5[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [ICON_PEACE]종교 분쟁에서 오는 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행이 감소하고, [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT개혁 교리[ENDCOLOR]를 선택할 수 있습니다. 도시의 [ICON_RELIGION]종교 압력이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]25%[ENDCOLOR] 증가하고 개종에 대한 도시의 저항이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]10%[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][COLOR_YELLOW]성도[ENDCOLOR]에만 건설할 수 있습니다. 전 세계에 당신 문명의 종교를 따르는 신도 수가 적어도 15% 이상 있어야 합니다. 이 불가사의는 문명당 하나만 건설할 수 있는 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]국가 불가사의[ENDCOLOR]입니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HOLY_COUNCIL">
			<Text>종교 공의회</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HOLY_COUNCIL_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Build the Holy Council for a boost to Food output and to improve all Holy Sites. Constructing this National Wonder will also allow you to choose a Reformation Belief. May only be constructed in a Holy City, and only if at least 15% of the global population follows your Religion (scaling with map size). Reduces [ICON_HAPPINESS_3] Religious Unrest, and allows you to select a Reformation Belief.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HOLY_COUNCIL_TEXT">
			<Text>An ecumenical council (or holy council) is a conference of ecclesiastical dignitaries and theological experts convened to discuss and settle matters of Church doctrine and practice in which those entitled to vote are convoked from the whole world (oikoumene) and which secures the approbation of the whole Church.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_APOSTOLIC_PALACE_HELP">
			<Text>도시의 [ICON_GOLDEN_AGE]황금기 점수가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]4[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. 모든 성지의 [ICON_GOLDEN_AGE]황금기 점수가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]5[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [ICON_PEACE]종교 분쟁에서 오는 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행이 감소하고, [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT개혁 교리[ENDCOLOR]를 선택할 수 있습니다. 도시의 [ICON_RELIGION]종교 압력이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]25%[ENDCOLOR] 증가하고 개종에 대한 도시의 저항이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]10%[ENDCOLOR]증가합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][COLOR_YELLOW]성도[ENDCOLOR]에만 건설할 수 있습니다. 전 세계에 당신 문명의 종교를 따르는 신도 수가 적어도 15% 이상 있어야 합니다. 이 불가사의는 문명당 하나만 건설할 수 있는 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]국가 불가사의[ENDCOLOR]입니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_APOSTOLIC_PALACE">
			<Text>사도 궁전</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_APOSTOLIC_PALACE_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Build the Apostolic Palace for more rapid Golden Ages and to improve all Holy Sites. Constructing this National Wonder will also allow you to choose a Reformation Belief. May only be constructed in a Holy City, and only if at least 15% of the global population follows your Religion (scaling with map size). Reduces [ICON_HAPPINESS_3] Religious Unrest, and allows you to select a Reformation Belief.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_APOSTOLIC_PALACE_TEXT">
			<Text>The Latin word basilica has three distinct applications in modern English. The word was originally used to describe an open, Roman, public court building, usually located adjacent to the forum of a Roman town. By extension it was applied to Christian buildings of the same form and continues to be used in an architectural sense to describe those buildings with a central nave and aisles. Later, the term came to refer specifically to a large and important church, the Apostolic Palace, that has been given special ceremonial rights by the Pope.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GRAND_OSSUARY_HELP">
			<Text>모든 성지의 [ICON_CULTURE]문화가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]5[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [ICON_PEACE]종교 분쟁에서 오는 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행이 감소하고, [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT개혁 교리[ENDCOLOR]를 선택할 수 있습니다. 도시의 [ICON_RELIGION]종교 압력이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]25%[ENDCOLOR] 증가하고 개종에 대한 도시의 저항이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]10%[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][COLOR_YELLOW]성도[ENDCOLOR]에만 건설할 수 있습니다. 전 세계에 당신 문명의 종교를 따르는 신도 수가 적어도 15% 이상 있어야 합니다. 이 불가사의는 문명당 하나만 건설할 수 있는 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]국가 불가사의[ENDCOLOR]입니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GRAND_OSSUARY">
			<Text>대 납골당</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GRAND_OSSUARY_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Build the Ossuary for lots of Faith and to improve all Holy Sites. Constructing this National Wonder will also allow you to choose a Reformation Belief. May only be constructed in a Holy City, and only if at least 15% of the global population follows your Religion (scaling with map size). Reduces [ICON_HAPPINESS_3] Religious Unrest, and allows you to select a Reformation Belief.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GRAND_OSSUARY_TEXT">
			<Text>An ossuary is a chest, box, building, well, or site made to serve as the final resting place of human skeletal remains. They are frequently used where burial space is scarce. A body is first buried in a temporary grave, then after some years the skeletal remains are removed and placed in an ossuary. The greatly reduced space taken up by an ossuary means that it is possible to store the remains of many more people in a single tomb than if the original coffins were left as is. In Persia, the Zoroastrians used a deep well for this function from the earliest times (circa 3,000 years ago) and called it astudan (literally, "the place for the bones"). There are many rituals and regulations in the Zoroastrian faith concerning the astudans. Among the pre-7th-century Sogdians in the region of central Asia, the name for an ossuary was tanbar.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BATH">
			<Text>목욕탕</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GROVE">
			<Text>자문회</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HERBALIST">
			<Text>약초상</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WELL">
			<Text>우물</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WIND_PLANT">
			<Text>풍력 발전소</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STOCKYARD">
			<Text>기업형 농장</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_COAL_PLANT">
			<Text>제련소</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MINEFIELD">
			<Text>지뢰밭</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GROVE_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Council generates Science every time city grows, and is availble very early. Build this building if you wish to have a technological advantage over your rivals, though the value of this advantage diminishes as the city becomes larger.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BATH_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Bath generates Culture, and boosts the Gold and Culture yield of Temples, Gardens, and Amphitheaters in the City. Also generates additional Culture during Golden Ages. Baths can be constructed only in cities next to fresh water.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HERBALIST_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Herbalist increases City growth, and improves the yields on nearby Jungle and Forest tiles as well as Plantations. Build them early to maximize the bonus, and to take advantage of regions with a large number of features.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WELL_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Well can only be constructed in a city not on a river. The Well increases the city's Production based on the city's population, but less efficiently than the Water Mill.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WIND_PLANT_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Wind Power is a modern electrical system. Wind Power increases the Production, Science, and Gold output of land tiles the city works. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Requires 1 [ICON_RES_IRON] Iron to be built.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GROCER_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Grocer is a Renaissance-era building which can only be constructed if you have already built an Aqueduct in the City. The Grocer helps your City grow more quickly, combats Poverty, and improves the tile yield of Bananas.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STOCKYARD_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Agribusiness is an Industrial-era building which can only be constructed if you have already built a Grocer in the City. An Agribusiness greatly improves the yields on your city's Farm and Pasture tiles, and boosts GPT significantly if your city has high Food yields. However, the use of Horses is a risky tradeoff during an era in which Cavalry is still quite powerful.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_COAL_PLANT_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Refinery is a Modern-era building which can only be constructed in 5 Cities total. The Refinery helps your Production and produces 1 Coal and 1 Iron Resource, however it has a high maintenance cost. Only construct if you find yourself without these vital late-game strategic resources.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MINEFIELD_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Minefield is a Modern-era building which can only be constructed if you have enough Iron and you have already built a Harbor in the City. The Minefield increases City Defense and Hit Points, and reduces the movement of enemy naval units and embarked units by 1.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GROVE_HELP">
			<Text>[ICON_CITIZEN]시민이 증가할 때 [ICON_RESEARCH]과학을 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]5[ENDCOLOR] [COLOR:105:105:105:255](시대별 보정)[ENDCOLOR] 제공합니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WELL_HELP">
			<Text>[ICON_CITIZEN]시민 5명마다 [ICON_PRODUCTION]생산이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][COLOR_NEGATIVE_TEXT]강과 인접한 도시[ENDCOLOR]에는 건설할 수 없습니다. 도시에 [COLOR_NEGATIVE_TEXT]물레방앗간[ENDCOLOR]이 없어야 건설할 수 있습니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HERBALIST_HELP">
			<Text>도시 주변 정글 또는 숲 타일 2개마다 [ICON_FOOD]식량이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. 재배지 및 야영지의 [ICON_PRODUCTION]생산이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BATH_HELP">
			<Text>사원, 원형극장, 정원의 [ICON_GOLD]골드 및 [ICON_CULTURE]문화가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [ICON_GOLDEN_AGE]황금기 동안 도시의 [ICON_CULTURE]문화가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]10%[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][COLOR_YELLOW]담수와 인접한 도시[ENDCOLOR]에만 건설할 수 있습니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GROCER_HELP">
			<Text>[ICON_CITIZEN]시민 5명마다 [ICON_FOOD]식량이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [ICON_CITIZEN]시민이 증가할 때 사용한 [ICON_FOOD]식량의 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]15%[ENDCOLOR]를 다음 [ICON_CITIZEN]시민을 위해 사용할 수 있습니다. [COLOR:105:105:105:255](이 효과는 송수로와 중첩됩니다.)[ENDCOLOR] [ICON_GOLD]빈곤에서 오는 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 감소합니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WIND_PLANT_HELP">
			<Text>산을 제외한 도시 주변 모든 지상 타일의 [ICON_PRODUCTION]생산, [ICON_RESEARCH]과학, [ICON_GOLD]골드가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]2[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_RES_IRON]철 [COLOR_NEGATIVE_TEXT]1개[ENDCOLOR]가 필요합니다. 도시에 다른 [COLOR_NEGATIVE_TEXT]발전소[ENDCOLOR]가 없어야 건설할 수 있습니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STOCKYARD_HELP">
			<Text>농장 및 목장의 [ICON_PRODUCTION]생산이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]2[ENDCOLOR] [ICON_GOLD] 골드가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]2[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. 매 턴 [ICON_FOOD]식량의 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]10%[ENDCOLOR]를 [ICON_GOLD]골드로 전환합니다. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_RES_HORSE]말 [COLOR_NEGATIVE_TEXT]2개[ENDCOLOR]가 필요합니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_COAL_PLANT_HELP">
			<Text>[ICON_RES_COAL]석탄 및 [ICON_RES_IRON]철 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1개[ENDCOLOR]를 제공합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]이 건물은 문명당 [COLOR_YELLOW]최대 5개[ENDCOLOR]까지 건설할 수 있습니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MINEFIELD_HELP">
			<Text>적 해상 유닛 및 승선 유닛이 이 도시의 영토에서 타일마다 [ICON_MOVES]이동력을 추가로 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 더 소모합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_RES_IRON]철 [COLOR_NEGATIVE_TEXT]1개[ENDCOLOR]가 필요합니다. [COLOR_YELLOW]해안 도시[ENDCOLOR]에만 건설할 수 있습니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_GROVE_TEXT">
			<Text>A Council is a governing body in an organised community. It is most common in subsistence cultures, with council membership being the condition or quality of being a political leader of a community. Over time, as communities grew, the importance of councils diminished in favor of larger governing institutions.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_BATH_TEXT">
			<Text>Throughout history, societies devised systems to enable water to be brought to population centres. Ancient Greece utilized small bathtubs, wash basins, and foot baths for personal cleanliness. The earliest findings of baths date from the mid-2nd millennium BC in the palace complex at Knossos, Crete, and the luxurious alabaster bathtubs excavated in Akrotiri, Santorini. The Greeks established public baths and showers within gymnasiums for relaxation and personal hygiene. In fact, the word gymnasium comes from the Greek word gymnos, meaning naked. Ancient Rome developed a network of aqueducts to supply water to all large towns and population centres and had indoor plumbing, with pipes that terminated in homes and at public wells and fountains. The Roman public baths were called thermae. With the fall of the Roman Empire the aqueduct network fell into disrepair and most of it ceased to be used. In the Middle Ages, bathing commonly took place in public bathhouses. However, public nudity was frowned upon by liturgical factions of the period. Public baths were also havens for prostitution, which created opposition to the public baths. Rich people bathed at home, most likely in their bedroom, as 'bath' rooms were not common. Bathing was done in large, wooden tubs with a linen cloth laid in it to protect the bather from splinters. Additionally, during the Renaissance and Protestant Reformation, the quality and condition of the clothing (as opposed to the actual cleanliness of the body itself) were thought to reflect the soul of an individual. Clean clothing also reflected one's social status; clothes made the man or woman. Additionally, from the late Middle Ages through to the end of the 18th century, etiquette and medical manuals advised people to only wash the parts of the body that were visible to the public; for example, the ears, hands, feet, and face and neck. This did away with the public baths and left the cleaning of oneself to the privacy of one's home.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_HERBALIST_TEXT">
			<Text>Herbalism is use of plants for medicinal purposes, and the study of such use. Plants have been the basis for medical treatments through much of human history, and such traditional medicine is still widely practiced today. Modern medicine recognizes herbalism as a form of alternative medicine, as the practice of herbalism is not strictly based on evidence gathered using the scientific method. Modern medicine, does, however, make use of many plant-derived compounds as the basis for evidence-tested pharmaceutical drugs, and phytotherapy works to apply modern standards of effectiveness testing to herbs and medicines that are derived from natural sources.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_WELL_TEXT">
			<Text>Wood-lined wells are known from the early Neolithic Linear Pottery culture, for example in Kückhoven (an outlying centre of Erkelenz), dated 5090 BC and Eythra, dated 5200 BC in Schletz (an outlying centre of Asparn an der Zaya) in Austria. Australian Aborigines relied on wells to survive the harsh Australian desert. They would dig down, scooping out sand and mud to reach clean water, then cover the source with spinifex to prevent spoilage. Non-Aborigines call these native wells, soaks or soakages. Stepwells are common in the west of India. In these wells, the water may be reached by descending a set of steps. They may be covered and are often of architectural significance. Many stepwells were also used for leisure, providing relief from the daytime heat. A qanat is an ancient water collection system made up of a series of wells and linked underground water channels that collects flowing water from a source usually a distance away, stores it, and then brings the water to the surface using gravity. Much of the population of Iran and other arid countries in Asia and North Africa historically depended upon the water from qanats; the areas of population corresponded closely to the areas where qanats are possible. In Egypt, shadoofs and sakiehs are used. When compared to each other however, the Sakkieh is much more efficient, as it can bring up water from a depth of 10 metres (versus the 3 metres of the shadoof). The Sakieh is the Egyptian version of the Noria. From the Iron Age onwards, wells are common archaeological features, both with wooden shafts and shaft linings made from wickerwork. The world's oldest known wells, located in Cyprus, date to 7500 BC. Two wells from the Neolithic period, around 6500 BC, have been discovered in Israel. One is in Atlit, on the northern coast of Israel, and the other is the Jezreel Valley.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_GROCER_TEXT">
			<Text>Beginning as early as the 14th century, a grocer (or "purveyor") was a dealer in comestible dry goods such as spices, peppers, sugar, and (later) cocoa, tea and coffee. These items were bought in bulk, hence the term grocer from the French "grossier" meaning wholesaler, this term derived from Medieval Latin "grossarius" from which we also derive the word gross (meaning a quantity of twelve dozen, or 144). As increasing numbers of staple foodstuffs became available in cans and other less-perishable packaging, the trade expanded its province. Today, grocers deal in a wide range of staple food-stuffs including such perishables as meats, produce and dairy products. Such goods are, hence, groceries.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_WIND_PLANT_TEXT">
			<Text>Wind power is the conversion of wind energy into a useful form of energy, such as using wind turbines to produce electrical power, windmills for mechanical power, windpumps for water pumping or drainage, or sails to propel ships. Large wind farms consist of hundreds of individual wind turbines which are connected to the electric power transmission network. For new constructions, onshore wind is an inexpensive source of electricity, competitive with or in many places cheaper than fossil fuel plants. Small onshore wind farms provide electricity to isolated locations. Utility companies increasingly buy surplus electricity produced by small domestic wind turbines. Offshore wind is steadier and stronger than on land, and offshore farms have less visual impact, but construction and maintenance costs are considerably higher. Wind power, as an alternative to fossil fuels, is plentiful, renewable, widely distributed, clean, produces no greenhouse gas emissions during operation and uses little land. The effects on the environment are generally less problematic than those from other power sources. As of 2011, Denmark is generating more than a quarter of its electricity from wind and 83 countries around the world are using wind power to supply the electricity grid. In 2010 wind energy production was over 2.5% of total worldwide electricity usage, and growing rapidly at more than 25% per annum. Wind power is very consistent from year to year but has significant variation over shorter time scales. As the proportion of windpower in a region increases, a need to upgrade the grid, and a lowered ability to supplant conventional production can occur. Power management techniques such as having excess capacity storage, geographically distributed turbines, dispatchable backing sources, storage such as pumped-storage hydroelectricity, exporting and importing power to neighboring areas or reducing demand when wind production is low, can greatly mitigate these problems.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_STOCKYARD_TEXT">
			<Text>Agribusiness is the business of agricultural production. The term was coined in 1957 by Goldberg and Davis. It includes agrichemicals, breeding, crop production (farming and contract farming), distribution, farm machinery, processing, and seed supply, as well as marketing and retail sales. All agents of the food and fiber value chain and those institutions that influence it are part of the agribusiness system. Within the agriculture industry, "agribusiness" is used simply as a portmanteau of agriculture and business, referring to the range of activities and disciplines encompassed by modern food production. There are academic degrees in and departments of agribusiness, agribusiness trade associations, agribusiness publications, and so forth, worldwide. Examples of agribusinesses include seed and agrichemical producers like Dow AgroSciences, DuPont, Monsanto, and Syngenta; AB Agri (part of Associated British Foods) animal feeds, biofuels, and micro-ingredients, ADM, grain transport and processing; John Deere, farm machinery producer; Ocean Spray, farmer's cooperative; and Purina Farms, agritourism farm.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_COAL_PLANT_TEXT">
			<Text>Refined coal is the product of the application of a coal upgrading technology that removes moisture and certain pollutants from lower-rank coals such as sub-bituminous and lignite (brown) coals and raising their calorific values. Coal refining or upgrading technologies are typically pre-combustion treatments and/or processes that alter the characteristics of a coal before it is burned. The goals of pre-combustion coal upgrading technologies are to increase efficiency and reduce emissions when coal is burned. Depending on the situation, pre-combustion technology can be used in place of or as a supplement to post-combustion technologies to control emissions from coal-fueled boilers. A primary benefit of refined coal is the capacity to reduce the net volume of carbon emissions that is currently emitted from power generators and would reduce the amount of emissions that is proposed to be managed via emerging carbon sequestration methodologies. Refined coal technologies have primarily been developed in the United States, several similar technologies have been researched, developed and tested in Victoria, Australia, including the Densified coal technology (Coldry Process) developed to alter the chemical bonds of brown coal to create a product that is cleaner, stable (not prone to spontaneous combustion), exportable and of sufficiently high calorific value to be a black coal equivalent.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_MINEFIELD_TEXT">
			<Text>A naval mine is a self-contained explosive device placed in water to damage or destroy surface ships or submarines. Unlike depth charges, mines are deposited and left to wait until they are triggered by the approach of, or contact with, an enemy vessel. Naval mines can be used offensively—to hamper enemy shipping movements or lock vessels into a harbour; or defensively—to protect friendly vessels and create "safe" zones.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SLATER_MILL">
			<Text>슬레이터 밀</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SLATER_MILL_HELP">
			<Text>[COLOR_YELLOW]공장[ENDCOLOR]을 무료로 제공합니다. 이 불가사의가 지어진 도시의 [ICON_PRODUCTION]생산이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]5[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [ICON_RES_COAL]석탄 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]4개[ENDCOLOR]를 제공합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][COLOR_YELLOW]강과 인접한 도시[ENDCOLOR]에만 건설할 수 있습니다. 이 불가사의는 전 세계에서 하나만 건설할 수 있는 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]세계 불가사의[ENDCOLOR]입니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_SLATER_MILL_TEXT">
			<Text>A National Historic Landmark, the Slater Mill is located next to the Blackstone River in Pawtucket, Rhode Island. Modeled after cotton spinning mills first established in England, the Slater Mill is the first water-powered cotton spinning mill in North America to utilize the Arkwright system of cotton spinning as developed by Richard Arkwright. Samuel Slater, the mill's founder, apprenticed as a young man in Belper, England with industrialist Jedediah Strutt. Shortly after immigrating to the United States, Slater was hired by Moses Brown of Providence, Rhode Island to produce a working set of machines necessary to spin cotton yarn using water-power. Construction of the machines, as well as a dam, waterway, waterwheel and mill was completed in 1793. Manufacturing was based on Richard Arkwright's cotton spinning system which included carding, drawing, and spinning machines. Slater initially hired children and families to work in his mill, establishing a pattern that was replicated throughout the Blackstone Valley and known as the "Rhode Island System". It was later eclipsed by Francis Cabot Lowell's Waltham System. Slater Mill was the first property to be listed on the National Register of Historic Places, and was designated a National Historic Landmark on November 13, 1966.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_SLATER_MILL_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"If I do not make as good of yarn as they do in England, I will have nothing for my services, but will throw the whole of what I have attempted over the bridge."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Samuel Slater[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MOTHERLAND_STATUE">
			<Text>어머니 조국상</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_MOTHERLAND_STATUE_HELP">
			<Text>[COLOR_MAGENTA]무료 정책[ENDCOLOR]을 1개 제공합니다. [COLOR_YELLOW]경찰서[ENDCOLOR]를 무료로 제공합니다. 적[ICON_SPY]스파이가 이 불가사의가 지어진 도시에서 [ICON_RESISTANCE]반란을 부추기거나  [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행을 야기시킬 수 없습니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_SPY]스파이가 고급 첩보 활동을 통해 건물의 [ICON_PRODUCTION]생산을 방해하고 [ICON_RESISTANCE]반란을 부추기거나  [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행을 야기시킬 가능성이 증가합니다. [ICON_FOOD]/[ICON_PRODUCTION]곤경에서 오는 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 감소합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_IDEOLOGY_ORDER][COLOR_MAGENTA]질서[ENDCOLOR] 이념을 채택해야 선택할 수 있습니다. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]이 불가사의는 전 세계에서 하나만 건설할 수 있는 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]세계 불가사의[ENDCOLOR]입니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_MOTHERLAND_STATUE_TEXT">
			<Text>The Motherland Calls, also called Mother Motherland, Mother Motherland Is Calling, simply The Motherland, or The Mamayev Monument, is a statue in Mamayev Kurgan in Volgograd, Russia, commemorating the Battle of Stalingrad. It was designed by sculptor Yevgeny Vuchetich and structural engineer Nikolai Nikitin, and declared the largest statue in the world in 1967. Compared with the later higher statues, The Motherland Calls is significantly more complex from an engineering point of view, due to its characteristic posture with a sword raised high in the right hand and the left hand extended in a calling gesture. The technology behind the statue is based on a combination of prestressed concrete with wire ropes structure, a solution which can be found also in another work of Nikitin's, the super-tall Ostankino Tower in Moscow. It is the tallest statue of a woman in the world.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MOTHERLAND_STATUE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Everyone imposes his own system as far as his army can reach."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Josef Stalin[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BLETCHLEY_PARK">
			<Text>블레츨리 파크</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BLETCHLEY_PARK_HELP">
			<Text>[COLOR_YELLOW]연구소[ENDCOLOR]를 무료로 제공합니다. 모든 과학자 전문가의 [ICON_RESEARCH]과학이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. 추가 [ICON_SPY][COLOR_YELLOW]스파이[ENDCOLOR]를 2명 또는 그 이상 [COLOR:105:105:105:255]([ICON_CITY_STATE]도시 국가 수에 기반)[ENDCOLOR] 제공하고 존재하는 모든 [ICON_SPY]스파이의 레벨이 상승합니다. 모든 도시에서 적[ICON_SPY]스파이의 효율이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]15%[ENDCOLOR] 감소합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]당신의 문명이 소유한 [ICON_SPY]스파이가 더이상 고급 첩보 활동에 실패하지 않습니다. 고급 첩보 활동을 통해 [ICON_RESEARCH]과학을 훔치거나 세계 불가사의 [ICON_PRODUCTION]건설을 방해할 가능성이 증가합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][COLOR_MAGENTA]합리주의[ENDCOLOR] 정책을 완성해야 건설할 수 있습니다. 이 불가사의는 전 세계에서 하나만 건설할 수 있는 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]세계 불가사의[ENDCOLOR]입니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_BLETCHLEY_PARK_TEXT">
			<Text>Bletchley Park, in Milton Keynes, Buckinghamshire, was the central site of the United Kingdom's Government Code and Cypher School, which during the Second World War regularly penetrated the secret communications of the Axis Power, most importantly the German Enigma and Lorenz ciphers. The official historian of World War II British Intelligence has written that the "Ultra" intelligence produced at Bletchley shortened the war by two to four years, and that without it the outcome of the war would have been uncertain. The site is now an educational and historical attraction memorialising and celebrating those accomplishments.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_BLETCHLEY_PARK_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Bletchley Park: the goose that laid the golden eggs and never cackled."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Winston Churchill[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_EMPIRE_STATE_BUILDING">
			<Text>엠파이어 스테이트 빌딩</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_EMPIRE_STATE_BUILDING_HELP">
			<Text>[COLOR_YELLOW]증권거래소[ENDCOLOR]를 무료로 제공합니다. 원하는 [ICON_GREAT_PEOPLE][COLOR_YELLOW]위인[ENDCOLOR]이 1명 출현합니다. 모든  전문가의 산출량이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]이 불가사의는 전 세계에서 하나만 건설할 수 있는 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]세계 불가사의[ENDCOLOR]입니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_EMPIRE_STATE_BUILDING_TEXT">
			<Text>The Empire State Building is a 103-story skyscraper located in Midtown Manhattan, New York City, at the intersection of Fifth Avenue and West 34th Street. It has a roof height of 1,250 feet (380 m), and with its antenna spire included, it stands a total of 1,454 feet (443 m) high.[6] Its name is derived from the nickname for New York, the Empire State. It stood as the world's tallest building for nearly 40 years, from its completion in early 1931 until the topping out of the original World Trade Center's North Tower in late 1970. Following the September 11 attacks in 2001, the Empire State Building was again the tallest building in New York (although it was no longer the tallest in the US or the world), until One World Trade Center reached a greater height on April 30, 2012. The Empire State Building is currently the fourth-tallest completed skyscraper in the United States (after the One World Trade Center, the Willis Tower and Trump International Hotel and Tower, both in Chicago), and the 25th-tallest in the world (the tallest now is Burj Khalifa, located in Dubai). It is also the fifth-tallest freestanding structure in the Americas.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_EMPIRE_STATE_BUILDING_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"The importance of money flows from it being a link between the present and the future."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - John Maynard Keynes[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CERN">
			<Text>유럽 입자물리 연구소</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CERN_HELP">
			<Text>[COLOR_RESEARCH_STORED]무료 기술[ENDCOLOR]을 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]2개[ENDCOLOR] 제공합니다. 모든 [ICON_CITY_STATE]도시 국가에 대한 [ICON_INFLUENCE]영향력을 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]100[ENDCOLOR] 제공합니다. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]이 불가사의는 전 세계에서 하나만 건설할 수 있는 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]세계 불가사의[ENDCOLOR]입니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_CERN_TEXT">
			<Text>The European Organization for Nuclear Research, known as CERN, is a European research organization whose purpose is to operate the world's largest particle physics laboratory. Established in 1954, the organization is based in the northwest suburbs of Geneva on the Franco–Swiss border, and has 21 European member states. Israel is the first (and currently only) non-European country granted full membership. The term CERN is also used to refer to the laboratory, which in 2013 counted 2513 staff members, and hosted some 12,313 fellows, associates, apprentices as well as visiting scientists and engineers representing 608 universities and research facilities and 113 nationalities. CERN's main function is to provide the particle accelerators and other infrastructure needed for high-energy physics research – as a result, numerous experiments have been constructed at CERN following international collaborations. It is also the birthplace of the World Wide Web. The main site at Meyrin has a large computer centre containing powerful data processing facilities, primarily for experimental-data analysis; because of the need to make these facilities available to researchers elsewhere, it has historically been a major wide area networking hub.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WONDER_CERN_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"When you look at a vacuum in a quantum theory of fields, it isn't exactly nothing."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Dr. Peter Higgs[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STUPA">
			<Text>사리탑</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STUPA_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Can only be built in cities following a religion with the Stupas belief. Construct this building by purchasing it with [ICON_PEACE] Faith. Build the Stupa to gain Faith, Golden Age Points and Tourism in the City.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STUPA_TEXT">
			<Text>A stupa is a mound-like or hemispherical structure containing Buddhist relics, typically the ashes of Buddhist monks, used by Buddhists as a place of meditation.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STUPA_HELP">
			<Text>도시의 [ICON_GOLDEN_AGE]황금기 점수가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]3[ENDCOLOR] [ICON_TOURISM]관광이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]5[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]도시의 [ICON_RELIGION]종교 압력이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]25%[ENDCOLOR] 증가하고 개종에 대한 도시의 저항이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]10%[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다.[ICON_RESEARCH]문맹에서 오는 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 감소합니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CHURCH">
			<Text>교회</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CHURCH_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Can only be built in cities following a religion with the Churches belief. Construct this building by purchasing it with [ICON_PEACE] Faith. Build the Church to gain Faith and a Great Work of Music slot in the City. Also makes missionaries more effective and begins "We Love the King Day" in the City.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CHURCH_TEXT">
			<Text>A church building, often simply called a church, is a building used for religious activities, particularly worship services. The term in its architectural sense is most often used by Christians to refer to their religious buildings but can be used by other religions. In traditional Christian architecture, the church is often arranged in the shape of a Christian cross. When viewed from plan view the longest part of a cross is represented by the aisle and the junction of the cross is located at the altar area.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CHURCH_HELP">
			<Text>건물이 완성되면 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]15턴[ENDCOLOR] 동안 "국왕 경축일"을 맞이합니다. [ICON_GREAT_WORK]걸작에서 오는 [ICON_PEACE]신앙이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]도시의 [ICON_RELIGION]종교 압력이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]40%[ENDCOLOR] 증가하고 개종에 대한 도시의 저항이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]10%[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [ICON_CULTURE]무료에서 오는 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 감소합니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MANDIR">
			<Text>만디르</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MANDIR_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Can only be built in cities following a religion with the Mandirs belief. Construct this building by purchasing it with [ICON_PEACE] Faith. Build the Mandir to gain Faith, Food, and a Great Work of Music slot in the City. Protects your City from certain Advanced Spy Actions.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MANDIR_TEXT">
			<Text>A Hindu temple is a house of god(s). It is a space and structure designed to bring human beings and gods together, infused with symbolism to express the ideas and beliefs of Hinduism.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MANDIR_HELP">
			<Text>도시의 [ICON_FOOD]식량이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]10%[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. 적[ICON_SPY]스파이가 이 도시에서 [ICON_GREAT_PEOPLE]위인을 암살하거나 유닛의 [ICON_PRODUCTION]생산을 방해할 수 없습니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]도시의 [ICON_RELIGION]종교 압력이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]25%[ENDCOLOR] 증가하고 개종에 대한 도시의 저항이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]10%[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [ICON_GOLD]빈곤에서 오는 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 감소합니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SYNAGOGUE">
			<Text>회당</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SYNAGOGUE_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Can only be built in cities following a religion with the Synagogues belief. Construct this building by purchasing it with [ICON_PEACE] Faith. Build the Synagogue to gain Faith, Production, and a Great Work of Writing slot in the City. The City generates more Science during "We Love the King Day."</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SYNAGOGUE_TEXT">
			<Text>A synagogue, also spelled synagog, is a Jewish house of prayer. Synagogues have a large hall for prayer (the main sanctuary), and may also have smaller rooms for study and sometimes a social hall and offices. Some have a separate room for Torah study, called the beth midrash.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SYNAGOGUE_HELP">
			<Text>"국왕 경축일"이 열리는 동안 도시의 [ICON_RESEARCH]과학이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]10%[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]도시의 [ICON_RELIGION]종교 압력이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]25%[ENDCOLOR] 증가하고 개종에 대한 도시의 저항이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]10%[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [ICON_FOOD]/[ICON_PRODUCTION]곤경에서 오는 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 감소합니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ORDER">
			<Text>기사단</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ORDER_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Can only be built in cities following a religion with the Orders belief. Construct this building by purchasing it with [ICON_PEACE] Faith. Build the Order to gain Faith, additional City Hit Points and [ICON_STRENGTH] Strength, +15 XP for all Military units, and the Morale promotion for your land Military units. Also grants +3 [ICON_PEACE] Faith when you kill an enemy Unit, scaling with Era.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ORDER_HELP">
			<Text>적 유닛을 처치할 때 [ICON_PEACE]신앙을 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]3[ENDCOLOR] [COLOR:105:105:105:255](시대별 보정)[ENDCOLOR] 제공합니다. 도시에서 생산하는 모든 군사 유닛의 경험치가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]15[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. 도시에서 생산하는 모든 지상 유닛에 [COLOR_PLAYER_PURPLE]사기[ENDCOLOR] 승급을 부여합니다. 도시의 체력과 [ICON_STRENGTH]전투력이 증가합니다. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]도시의 [ICON_RELIGION]종교 압력이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]25%[ENDCOLOR] 증가하고 개종에 대한 도시의 저항이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]10%[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [ICON_FOOD]/[ICON_PRODUCTION]곤경에서 오는 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 감소합니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ORDER_TEXT">
			<Text>A military order is any one of a variety of Christian societies of knights that were founded from the Middle Ages onwards for the purpose of crusading – propagating or defending the faith (originally Catholic, and after the Reformation sometimes Protestant), either in the Holy Land or against Islam (as, for example, during the Reconquista) or pagans (mainly in the Baltic region) in Europe. Many orders have, since the end of the Crusades and the Ottoman incursions, become secularized, and are usually represented by Roman Catholic ceremonial, missionary and charitable organizations in modern times.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Cathedral/Mosque/Pagoda-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CATHEDRAL_HELP">
			<Text>농장, 목장, 채석장의 [ICON_GOLD]골드가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. 도시의 국경이 확장될 때 [ICON_GOLD]골드를 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]10[ENDCOLOR] [COLOR:105:105:105:255](시대별 보정)[ENDCOLOR] 제공합니다. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]도시의 [ICON_RELIGION]종교 압력이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]25%[ENDCOLOR] 증가하고 개종에 대한 도시의 저항이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]10%[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [ICON_GOLD]빈곤에서 오는 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 감소합니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MOSQUE_HELP">
			<Text>[ICON_GOLDEN_AGE]황금기 동안 도시의 [ICON_CULTURE]문화가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]15%[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]도시의 [ICON_RELIGION]종교 압력이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]25%[ENDCOLOR] 증가하고 개종에 대한 도시의 저항이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]10%[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [ICON_RESEARCH]문맹에서 오는 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 감소합니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PAGODA_HELP">
			<Text>도시의 [ICON_CITIZEN]시민이 따르는 세계 종교 1개마다 모든 도시의 산출량이  [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [ICON_CULTURE]무료에서 오는 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] [ICON_PEACE]종교 분쟁에서 오는 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]2[ENDCOLOR] 감소합니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_THRONE_ROOM">
			<Text>알현실</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CAPITAL_THRONE_ROOM_HELP">
			<Text>[ICON_CAPITAL]수도에 음악가 전문가 슬롯을 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1개[ENDCOLOR] 제공합니다. [ICON_GREAT_WORK]걸작 음악 슬롯을 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1개[ENDCOLOR] 포함합니다. [ICON_GOLDEN_AGE]황금기의 길이가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]25%[ENDCOLOR] 증가하고 모든 도시의 산출량이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]10%[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. 군사 유닛 보급 한도가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]4[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. 전문가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]2명[ENDCOLOR]이 더이상 도시화에서 오는 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행을 증가시키지 않습니다.  [NEWLINE][NEWLINE][COLOR_MAGENTA]전통[ENDCOLOR] 정책을 완성해야 건설할 수 있습니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CAPITAL_THRONE_ROOM_PEDIA">
			<Text>A throne room is the room, often rather a hall, in the official residence of the crown, either a palace or a fortified castle, where the throne of a senior figure (usually a monarch) is set up with elaborate pomp— usually raised, often with steps, and under a canopy, both of which are part of the original notion of the Greek word thronos.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_TREASURY">
			<Text>국고</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_TREASURY_HELP">
			<Text>[ICON_CAPITAL]수도에 상인 전문가 슬롯을 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1개[ENDCOLOR] 제공합니다. 도시의 [ICON_GREAT_PEOPLE]위인 출현율이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]25%[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE][COLOR_MAGENTA]존엄[ENDCOLOR] 정책을 채택해야 건설할 수 있습니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_TREASURY_PEDIA">
			<Text>The term treasury was first used in Classical times to describe the votive buildings erected to house gifts to the gods, such as the Siphnian Treasury in Delphi or many similar buildings erected in Olympia, Greece by competing city-states to impress others during the ancient Olympic Games. In Ancient Greece treasuries were almost always physically incorporated within religious buildings such as temples, thus making state funds sacrosanct and adding moral constraints to the penal ones to those who would have access to these funds.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CAPITAL_ENGINEER">
			<Text>근위병 초소</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CAPITAL_ENGINEER_HELP">
			<Text>[ICON_CAPITAL]수도에 기술자 전문가 슬롯을 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1개[ENDCOLOR] 제공합니다. 도시의 방어력 및 체력이 증가합니다. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE][COLOR_MAGENTA]정의[ENDCOLOR] 정책을 채택해야 건설할 수 있습니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CAPITAL_ENGINEER_PEDIA">
			<Text>A Royal Guard describes any group of military bodyguards, soldiers or armed retainers responsible for the protection of a royal person, such as Emperor/Empress, King/Queen, or Prince/Princess. They often are an elite unit of the regular armed forces, or are designated as such, and may maintain special rights or privileges.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_GARDEN">
			<Text>궁전 정원</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_GARDEN_HELP">
			<Text>[ICON_CAPITAL]수도에 작가 전문가 슬롯을 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1개[ENDCOLOR] 제공합니다. [ICON_GREAT_WORK]걸작 문학 슬롯을 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1개[ENDCOLOR] 포함합니다. 모든 기념비, 정원, 목욕탕의 [ICON_CULTURE]문화가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]2[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][COLOR_MAGENTA]탁월[ENDCOLOR] 정책을 채택해야 건설할 수 있습니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_GARDEN_PEDIA">
			<Text>A garden is a planned space, usually outdoors, set aside for the display, cultivation, and enjoyment of plants and other forms of nature. The garden can incorporate both natural and man-made materials. The most common form today is known as a residential garden, but the term garden has traditionally been a more general one. Zoos, which display wild animals in simulated natural habitats, were formerly called zoological gardens.[1][2] Western gardens are almost universally based on plants, with garden often signifying a shortened form of botanical garden.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_COURT_CHAPEL">
			<Text>궁정 예배당</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_COURT_CHAPEL_HELP">
			<Text>[ICON_CAPITAL]수도에 예술가 전문가 슬롯을 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1개[ENDCOLOR] 제공합니다. [ICON_GREAT_WORK]걸작 예술품 슬롯을 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1개[ENDCOLOR] 포함합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][COLOR_MAGENTA]주권[ENDCOLOR] 정책을 채택해야 건설할 수 있습니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_COURT_CHAPEL_PEDIA">
			<Text>A chapel is a religious place of fellowship, prayer and worship that is attached to a larger, often nonreligious institution or that is considered an extension of a primary religious institution. It may be part of a larger structure or complex, such as a college, hospital, palace, prison, funeral home, church, synagogue or mosque, located on board a military or commercial ship, or it may be an entirely free-standing building, sometimes with its own grounds. Many military installations have chapels for the use of military personnel, normally under the leadership of a military chaplain.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_ASTROLOGER">
			<Text>궁정 점술가</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_ASTROLOGER_HELP">
			<Text>[ICON_CAPITAL]수도에 과학자 전문가 슬롯을 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1개[ENDCOLOR] 제공합니다. 모든 자문회 및 약초상의 [ICON_RESEARCH]과학이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]3[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][COLOR_MAGENTA]의식[ENDCOLOR] 정책을 채택해야 건설할 수 있습니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PALACE_ASTROLOGER_PEDIA">
			<Text>Astrology, in its broadest sense, is the search for meaning in the sky. Early evidence for humans making conscious attempts to measure, record, and predict seasonal changes by reference to astronomical cycles, appears as markings on bones and cave walls, which show that lunar cycles were being noted as early as 25,000 years ago. This was a first step towards recording the Moon's influence upon tides and rivers, and towards organising a communal calendar. Farmers addressed agricultural needs with increasing knowledge of the constellations that appear in the different seasons—and used the rising of particular star-groups to herald annual floods or seasonal activities. By the 3rd millennium BCE, civilisations had sophisticated awareness of celestial cycles, and may have oriented temples in alignment with heliacal risings of the stars.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_INDUS_CANAL">
			<Text>하라파 저수지</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_INDUS_CANAL_TEXT">
			<Text>The ancient Harappan and Indus Valley Civilizations of Northwest South Asia, including Pakistan and parts of India, were prominent in hydraulic engineering, and had many water supply and sanitation devices that were the first of their kind. Among other things, they contained the world's earliest known system of flush toilets. These existed in many homes, and were connected to a common sewerage pipe. Most houses also had private wells. City walls functioned as a barrier against floods, and massive reservoirs were often constructed along these walls to collect this floodwater to save for droughts.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_INDUS_CANAL_HELP">
			<Text>송수로를 대체하는 인도의 고유 건물입니다. [ICON_CITIZEN]시민이 증가할 때 사용한 [ICON_FOOD]식량의 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]20%[ENDCOLOR]를 다음 [ICON_CITIZEN]시민을 위해 사용할 수 있습니다. [ICON_CITIZEN]시민이 증가할 때 현재 [ICON_PRODUCTION]생산 산출량의 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]25%[ENDCOLOR]를 즉시 제공합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]도시 주변 범람원 타일의 [ICON_PRODUCTION]생산이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 증가하고 도시 주변 오아시스 및 호수 타일의 [ICON_FOOD]식량이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]2[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. 농장의 [ICON_FOOD]식량 및 [ICON_PRODUCTION]생산이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_GOLD]빈곤에서 오는 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 감소합니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_INDUS_CANAL_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Build these unique Aqueducts to rapidly increase your city's population size and productivity, especially if the city is settled on or near Flood Plainss.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DOJO">
			<Text>도조</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_DOJO_TEXT">
			<Text>A dojo is a Japanese term which literally means "place of the way". Initially, dōjōs were adjunct to temples. The term can refer to a formal training place for any of the Japanese do arts[which?] but typically it is considered the formal gathering place for students of any Japanese martial arts style such as karate, judo, or samurai, to conduct training, examinations and other related encounters. The concept of a dōjō only referring to a training place specifically for Asian martial arts is a Western concept; in Japan, any physical training facility, including professional wrestling schools, may be called dōjō because of its close martial arts roots.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DOJO_HELP">
			<Text>무기고를 대체하는 일본의 고유 건물입니다. 군사 유닛 보급 한도가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]2[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. 도시에서 생산하는 모든 유닛의 경험치가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]25[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]도시에서 생산하는 모든 기마, 근접, 화약, 장갑 유닛에 [COLOR_PLAYER_PURPLE]무사도[ENDCOLOR] 승급을 부여합니다. 유닛이 승급할 때 현재의 레벨에 기반한 [ICON_CULTURE]문화 및 [ICON_RESEARCH]과학을 제공합니다. [ICON_FOOD]/[ICON_PRODUCTION]곤경에서 오는 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 감소합니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DOJO_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Build these unique Armories to produce dominant military units. Does not require a Barracks. All Melee, Mounted, Gun, and Armor units trained in this city receive the Eight Virtues of Bushido Promotion, which offers one of eight possible promotions to these unit types after their first combat and increases the Unit's power as it takes damage.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ODEON">
			<Text>아크로폴리스</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_ODEON_TEXT">
			<Text>An acropolis is a settlement, especially a citadel, built upon an area of elevated ground—frequently a hill with precipitous sides, chosen for purposes of defense. In many parts of the world, acropoleis became the nuclei of large cities of classical antiquity, such as ancient Rome, and for this reason they are sometimes prominent landmarks in modern cities with ancient pasts, such as modern Rome. The word acropolis literally means in Greek "upper city," and though associated primarily with the Greek cities Athens, Argos ( with Larissa), Thebes (with Cadmea), and Corinth (with its Acrocorinth), may be applied generically to all such citadels, including Rome, Jerusalem, Celtic Bratislava, many in Asia Minor, or even Castle Rock in Edinburgh. An example in Ireland is the Rock of Cashel. Acropolis is also the term used by archaeologists and historians for the urban Castro culture settlements located in Northwestern Iberian hilltops.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ODEON_HELP">
			<Text>원형극장을 대체하는 그리스의 고유 건물입니다. 도시의 [ICON_TOURISM]관광이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]3[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. 도시의 [ICON_GREAT_WRITER]위대한 작가 출현율이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]33%[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. 모든 작가 길드의 [ICON_GOLD]골드가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [ICON_GREAT_WORK]걸작 문학 슬롯 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]2개[ENDCOLOR]를 포함합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]적 유닛을 처치할 때 이 도시에 [ICON_CULTURE_LOCAL]국경 확장 점수를 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]5[ENDCOLOR] [COLOR:105:105:105:255](시대별 보정)[ENDCOLOR] 제공합니다. 유닛이 이 도시에서 생산 되었다면 추가로 [ICON_CULTURE]문화를 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]25[ENDCOLOR] [COLOR:105:105:105:255](시대별 보정)[ENDCOLOR] 제공합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]테마보너스:  [ICON_CULTURE]문화 +2[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_RES_DYE] 염료: [ICON_CULTURE]문화 +1 [ICON_GOLD]골드 +1[NEWLINE][ICON_RES_SILK] 비단: [ICON_CULTURE]문화 +1 [ICON_GOLD]골드 +1</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ODEON_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Unique Greek replacement for the Amphitheater. Build Acropoli to boost your city's Defense, Culture, and Tourism, especially while at war for the latter two. Also boosts the City''s Great Writer rate and the value of Writers'' Guilds. Produces +3 [ICON_TOURISM] Tourism.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FLAVIAN_COLOSSEUM">
			<Text>콜로세움</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDING_FLAVIAN_COLOSSEUM_TEXT">
			<Text>The Flavian Amphitheater, or Colosseum, is one of the most famous venues in all of history. Though Ancient Rome had only one Colosseum, variations on the design were reproduced throughout the empire, and to the present day. A colosseum is an outdoor venue where the public can watch sports events. Depending upon the time and place, the events might be gladiatorial contests, American football games, or soccer matches. Of the three contests mentioned, the gladiatorial battles were perhaps the hardest on the players involved, the soccer matches (occasionally) just about as dangerous for the participants.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FLAVIAN_COLOSSEUM_HELP">
			<Text>투기장을 대체하는 로마의 고유 건물입니다. 도시의 [ICON_TOURISM]관광이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]2[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. 적 유닛을 처치할 때 [ICON_GOLDEN_AGE]황금기 점수를 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]5[ENDCOLOR] [COLOR:105:105:105:255](시대별 보정)[ENDCOLOR] 제공합니다. 유닛이 이 도시에서 생산 되었다면 추가로 [ICON_GREAT_PEOPLE]위대한 장군/위대한 제독 점수를 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]10[ENDCOLOR] [COLOR:105:105:105:255](시대별 보정)[ENDCOLOR] 제공합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]병영, 대장간, 무기고의 [ICON_PRODUCTION]생산이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]2[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [ICON_CONNECTED]도시 연결에서 오는 [ICON_GOLD]골드가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]2%[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [ICON_CULTURE]무료에서 오는 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 감소합니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FLAVIAN_COLOSSEUM_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Unique Roman replacement for the Arena. Build the Colosseum to boost your city's Culture, Tourism, and Production, and to maximize your empire's gain from the victories of your conquering armies. Every Colosseum slightly increases the Gold value of City Connections, thus allowing Rome to benefit from large, sprawling empires.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WHITE_TOWER">
			<Text>화이트 타워</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_WHITE_TOWER_TEXT">
			<Text>The White Tower is the old keep at the Tower of London. It was built by William the Conqueror during the early 1080s, and was later extended. The White Tower was the castle's strongest defensive point, and originally housed the king and his representatives. Throughout its long history, the Tower has been many things to England: A symbol of tyranny, a treasury, a menagerie, a mint, a palace and a prison. Today, the Tower of London is a vast museum which boasts, amongst its many treasures, the Crown Jewels of the English Monarchy.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WHITE_TOWER_HELP">
			<Text>국가 정보국을 대체하는 영국의 고유 건물입니다. [ICON_GREAT_WORK]걸작 예술품이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1개[ENDCOLOR] 들어 있는 [ICON_GREAT_WORK]걸작 슬롯을 포함합니다. 모든 도시에서 적[ICON_SPY]스파이의 효율이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]10%[ENDCOLOR] 감소합니다. 추가 [ICON_SPY][COLOR_YELLOW]스파이[ENDCOLOR] 1명 또는 그 이상을 [COLOR:105:105:105:255]([ICON_CITY_STATE]도시 국가 수에 기반)[ENDCOLOR] 제공하고 존재하는 모든 [ICON_SPY]스파이의 레벨이 상승합니다. [ICON_SPY]스파이가 고급 첩보 활동을 통해 [ICON_GREAT_PEOPLE]위인을 암살할 가능성이 증가합니다. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]모든 도시의 [ICON_FOOD]/[ICON_PRODUCTION]곤경에서 오는 요구 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행 수치가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]10%[ENDCOLOR] 감소합니다. [ICON_GREAT_WORK]걸작이나 [ICON_RESEARCH]기술을 훔칠 때, [ICON_CITY_STATE]도시 국가 쿠데타 및 선거 조작 성공 시, 또는 이 도시에 잠입한 적[ICON_SPY]스파이를 처치할 때 [ICON_RESEARCH]과학  [ICON_GOLD]골드를 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]20[ENDCOLOR] [COLOR:105:105:105:255](시대별 보정, 고급 첩보 활동은 추가 [ICON_GOLD]/[ICON_RESEARCH]5) )[ENDCOLOR] 제공합니다. 모든 경찰대, 성, 무기고의 [ICON_CULTURE]문화가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]도시에 [COLOR_YELLOW]경찰서[ENDCOLOR]가 있어야 건설할 수 있습니다. 문명에 도시가 많을수록 건설에 필요한 [ICON_PRODUCTION]생산과 [ICON_CITIZEN]시민이 증가합니다. 이 불가사의는 문명당 하나만 건설할 수 있는 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]국가 불가사의[ENDCOLOR]입니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WHITE_TOWER_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Unique English replacement for the National Intelligence Agency. The White Tower is available significantly earlier than the National Intelligence Agency, however yields from Spy Actions are reduced slightly as a result. In addition to the bonuses from the National Intelligence Agency, the White Tower improves Constabularies and Police Stations, contains a Great Work of Art, and provides yields for enemy Spies killed in the City.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_THE_CROWN_JEWELS_QUOTE">
			<Text>"On the contrary. Every Bison dollar will be worth[NEWLINE] five British pounds. For that is the exchange rate[NEWLINE] that the bank of England will implement after[NEWLINE] I kidnap their queen."[NEWLINE]-M. Bison</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_THE_CROWN_JEWELS">
			<Text>크라운 쥬얼스</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SIEGE_WORKSHOP">
			<Text>공성 주조 공장</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_SIEGE_WORKSHOP_TEXT">
			<Text>A foundry is a factory that produces metal castings. Metals are cast into shapes by melting them into a liquid, pouring the metal in a mold, and removing the mold material or casting after the metal has solidified as it cools. The most common metals processed are aluminium and cast iron. However, other metals, such as bronze, brass, steel, magnesium, and zinc, are also used to produce castings in foundries. In this process, parts of desired shapes and sizes can be formed. In the context of war, foundries were essential to the production of cannonry and other essential siege equipment.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SIEGE_WORKSHOP_HELP">
			<Text>대장간을 대체하는 오스만의 고유 건물입니다. 광산의 [ICON_PRODUCTION]생산이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]2[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. 공성 유닛을 생산할 때 [ICON_PRODUCTION]생산 보너스를 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]50%[ENDCOLOR] 제공하고 도시에서 생산하는 모든 공성 유닛에 [COLOR_PLAYER_PURPLE]일제 사격[ENDCOLOR] 승급을 부여합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]도시에서 유닛을 생산할 때 유닛 [ICON_PRODUCTION]생산 비용의 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]20%[ENDCOLOR]를 [ICON_RESEARCH]과학으로 전환합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_RES_IRON] 철: [ICON_PRODUCTION]생산 +1 [ICON_GOLD]골드 +1[NEWLINE][ICON_RES_COPPER] 구리: [ICON_PRODUCTION]생산 +1 [ICON_GOLD]골드 +1</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SIEGE_WORKSHOP_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Unique Ottoman replacement for the Forge. Generates extra Science from producing military units, produces Siege units much more quickly than normal, and grants them the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Volley[ENDCOLOR] Promotion for free. Use these attributes to build a massive force of artillery to take down an enemy's walls and conquer their lands!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MOMA">
			<Text>스미스소니언</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_THEMING_BONUS_MOMA">
			<Text>스미스소니언 기록 보관소</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_MOMA_THEMING_BONUS_HELP">
			<Text>보너스를 극대화 하려면 모든 걸작 슬롯을 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]다른 시대[ENDCOLOR]에 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]다른 문명[ENDCOLOR]이 만든 [COLOR_YELLOW]예술품[ENDCOLOR]으로 채우십시오.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_MOMA_TEXT">
			<Text>The Smithsonian Institution, established in 1846 "for the increase and diffusion of knowledge," is a group of museums and research centers administered by the Government of the United States. Originally organized as the "United States National Museum," that name ceased to exist as an administrative entity in 1967. Termed "the nation's attic" for its eclectic holdings of 138 million items, the Institution's nineteen museums, nine research centers, and zoo include historical and architectural landmarks, mostly located in the District of Columbia. Additional facilities are located in Arizona, Maryland, Massachusetts, New York City, Virginia, and Panama. A further 170 museums are Smithsonian Affiliates. The Institution's thirty million annual visitors are admitted without charge. Funding comes from the Institution's endowment, private and corporate contributions, membership dues, government support, as well as retail, concession and licensing revenues. Institution publications include Smithsonian and Air and Space magazines.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MOMA_HELP">
			<Text>에르미타슈 박물관을 대체하는 미국의 고유 건물입니다. [ICON_CITIZEN]시민 4명마다 [ICON_CULTURE]문화가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. 도시의 [ICON_CULTURE]문화가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]25%[ENDCOLOR] 증가하고 세계 불가사의, 자연 경관 및 타일 시설이 제공하는 [ICON_CULTURE]문화의 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]50%[ENDCOLOR]가 도시의 [ICON_TOURISM]관광에 추가됩니다. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]모든 박물관 및 방송탑의 [ICON_CULTURE]문화 및 [ICON_RESEARCH]과학이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]5[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다.[ICON_GREAT_WORK]걸작 예술품 슬롯 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]3개[ENDCOLOR]를 포함합니다. 모든 도시의 [ICON_CULTURE]무료에서 오는 요구 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행 수치가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]10%[ENDCOLOR] 감소합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]테마보너스:  [ICON_CULTURE]문화 +5[ICON_RESEARCH]과학 +5[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]도시에 [COLOR_YELLOW]오페라 극장[ENDCOLOR] 있어야 건설할 수 있습니다. 문명에 도시가 많을수록 건설에 필요한 [ICON_PRODUCTION]생산과 [ICON_CITIZEN]시민이 증가합니다. 이 불가사의는 문명당 하나만 건설할 수 있는 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]국가 불가사의[ENDCOLOR]입니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MOMA_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Unique American replacement for the Hermitage. In addition to the bonuses of the Hermitage, the Smithsonian boosts Culture and Tourism in the City greatly. The Smithsonian also boosts the Culture and Science output of all Museums and Broadcast Towers in your Empire. The Smithsonian is available slightly later than the Hermitage, however. The [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production Cost and [ICON_CITIZEN] Population Requirements increase based on the number of cities you own.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_THEMING_BONUS_AMPHITHEATER_NATIONAL">
			<Text>국가서사시</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_THEMING_BONUS_AMPHITHEATER_GLOBAL">
			<Text>국제서사시</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_AMPHITHEATER_THEMING_BONUS_HELP">
			<Text>보너스를 극대화 하려면 모든 걸작 슬롯을 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]같은 문명[ENDCOLOR]이 만든 [COLOR_YELLOW]문학[ENDCOLOR]으로 채우십시오.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MISSION">
			<Text>전도관</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_MISSION_TEXT">
			<Text>The history of Spain's missions in the American South and Southwest reveals much about Spain's strategy, contributions, and failures in these regions. The expeditions of Francisco Vázquez de Coronado (1540 42) and Juan de Oñate (1598) convinced Spanish authorities that no wealthy Indian empires like that of the Aztecs were to be found north of Mexico. Consequently the Spanish came to view the northern frontier of their empire as a defensive barrier and as a place where pagan souls might be saved. In what are now the states of Florida, Texas, New Mexico, Arizona, and California, missions were founded to propagate the doctrines of the Roman Catholic church. To protect these missions as well as the mines and ranches of Mexico from attack from the north, the Spanish established presidios fortified garrisons of troops. Franciscan priests founded a series of missions in Florida after 1573, mainly along the Atlantic and Gulf coasts. The first missions in New Mexico were established by friars accompanying Oñate's expedition of 1598; during the next 100 years Franciscan priests founded more than 40 additional missions, most of them along the Rio Grande. Especially influential was Father Alonso de Benavides, who directed the founding of 10 missions between 1625 and 1629 and thereafter promoted them ably in Spain. By 1680 missions had been established among most of the New Mexican Indians.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MISSION_HELP">
			<Text>성을 대체하는 스페인의 고유 건물입니다. [ICON_CITIZEN]시민이 증가할 때 현재 [ICON_PEACE]신앙 및 [ICON_GOLD]골드 산출량의 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]세 배[ENDCOLOR]를 즉시 제공합니다. 채석장의 [ICON_PRODUCTION]생산이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. 도시의 [ICON_RELIGION]종교 압력이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]15%[ENDCOLOR] 증가하고 개종에 대한 도시의 저항이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]15%[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]군사 유닛 보급 한도가 [ICON_CITIZEN]시민의 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]10%[ENDCOLOR]만큼 증가합니다. [ICON_GREAT_WORK]걸작 예술품 슬롯 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1개[ENDCOLOR]를 포함합니다. 도시의 전역 요구 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행 수치가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]5%[ENDCOLOR] 감소합니다[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][COLOR_YELLOW]성[ENDCOLOR]이 없어도 건설할 수 있습니다. [ICON_PEACE]신앙으로 구매할 수 있습니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MISSION_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Unique Spanish replacement for the Castle. It is cheaper than the Castle, has no maintenance, does not require Walls in order to be built, and can be purchased with Faith. Grants a bunch of Faith and Gold when Citizens are born in City (based on the current yields of the city when the new citizen is born). Increases Military Units supplied by this City's population by 10%. Boosts the city's religious pressure by 15% and resistance to foreign conversion by 15%, thus making the city more effective at converting nearby cities. Build these unique Castles to quickly boost a City's Defense, bypass the need for Walls, and to bolster your Religion. Also helps with managing the Empire Needs Modifier in this City.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JELLING_STONES">
			<Text>룬스톤</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JELLING_STONES_PEDIA">
			<Text>A runestone is typically a raised stone with a runic inscription, but the term can also be applied to inscriptions on boulders and on bedrock. The tradition began in the 4th century and lasted into the 12th century, but most of the runestones date from the late Viking Age. Most runestones are located in Scandinavia, but there are also scattered runestones in locations that were visited by Norsemen during the Viking Age. Runestones are often memorials to dead men. Runestones were usually brightly coloured when erected, though this is no longer evident as the colour has worn off.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JELLING_STONES_HELP">
			<Text>등대를 대체하는 덴마크의 고유 건물입니다. 이 도시에서 생산하는 유닛이 타일을 약탈할 때 [ICON_GOLD]골드 및 [ICON_CULTURE]문화를 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]30[ENDCOLOR] [COLOR:105:105:105:255](시대별 보정)[ENDCOLOR] 제공합니다. 지상 및 해상 유닛을 생산할 때 [ICON_PRODUCTION]생산 보너스를 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]25%[ENDCOLOR] 제공합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]도시 주변 해양 타일의 [ICON_FOOD]식량이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]2[ENDCOLOR] [ICON_GOLD]골드가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. 이 도시에서 출발하는 국내 [ICON_TURNS_REMAINING]교역로의 [ICON_FOOD]식량이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]6[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_CONNECTED]육상으로 연결되지 않은 도시와 [ICON_CAPITAL]수도를 [ICON_CONNECTED]해안 도시로 연결합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][COLOR_YELLOW]해안 도시[ENDCOLOR]에만 건설할 수 있습니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JELLING_STONES_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Unique Danish replacement for the Lighthouse. In addition to the Lighthouse's bonuses, Runestones produce [ICON_CULTURE] Culture and [ICON_GOLD] Gold when units from this City pillage tiles (Roads and Railroads do not count), generates more Food from ocean tiles, and increases production of melee land and naval units. Unlike the Lighthouse, the City does not have to be built on the coast.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SEOWON">
			<Text>서원</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_SEOWON_TEXT">
			<Text>Seowon were the most common educational institution of Korea during the mid- to late Joseon Dynasty. They were private institutions, and combined the functions of a Confucian shrine and a preparatory school. In educational terms, the seowon were primarily occupied with preparing students for the national civil service examinations. In most cases, seowon served only pupils of the aristocratic yangban class.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SEOWON_HELP">
			<Text>대학을 대체하는 한국의 고유 건물입니다. 도시 주변 정글 타일의 [ICON_RESEARCH]과학이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다. [ICON_GREAT_WORK]걸작에서 오는 [ICON_PRODUCTION]생산 및 [ICON_RESEARCH]과학이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_GOLDEN_AGE]황금기 동안 도시의 [ICON_RESEARCH]과학이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]15%[ENDCOLOR] 증가합니다.[ICON_CITIZEN]시민이 증가할 때 현재 [ICON_RESEARCH]과학 산출량의 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]50%[ENDCOLOR]를 즉시 제공합니다. [ICON_RESEARCH]문맹에서 오는 [ICON_HAPPINESS_3]불행이 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]1[ENDCOLOR] 감소합니다.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SEOWON_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Unique Korean replacement for the University. Generates more Science and Production than the University, generates Faith, and is available earlier. The increased Great Person rate will help you produce Great People more quickly, thus helping you to maximize Korea's Unique Ability.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_YURT">
			<Text>게르</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_YURT_TEXT">
			<Text>A yurt, called a 'Ger' by Mongolians, is a portable, bent dwelling structure traditionally used by nomads in the steppes of Central Asia as their home. The structure comprises a crown or compression wheel, usually steam bent, supported by roof ribs which are bent down at the end where they meet the lattice wall (again, steam bent). The top of the wall is prevented from spreading by means of a tension band which opposes the force of the roof ribs. The structure is usually covered by layers of fabric and sheep's wool felt for insulation and weatherproofing. The traditional decoration within a yurt is primarily pattern based. These patterns are generally not according to taste, but are derived from sacred ornaments with certain symbolism. Symbols representing strength are among the most common, including the khas (swastika) and four powerful beasts (lion, tiger, garuda and dragon), as well as stylized representations of the five elements (fire, water, earth, metal, and wood), considered to be the fundamental, unchanging elements of the cosmos. Such patterns are commonly used in the home with the belief that they will bring strength and offer protection.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_YURT_HELP">
			<Text>곡창을 대체하는 몽골의 고유 건물입니다. 건물이 완성되면 도시에 [ICON_FOOD]식량을 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]25[ENDCOLOR] 제공합니다. [ICON_CITIZEN]시민이 증가할 때 사용한 [ICON_FOOD]식량의 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]15%[ENDCOLOR]를 다음 [ICON_CITIZEN]시민을 위해 사용할 수 있습니다. 새로운 타일을 확보하기 위해 필요한 [ICON_CULTURE]문화 및 [ICON_GOLD]골드가 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]25%[ENDCOLOR] 감소합니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]국내 교역로를 통해 당신 문명의 다른 도시로 [ICON_FOOD]식량을 [ICON_TURNS_REMAINING]제공할 수 있습니다.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_RES_WHEAT] 밀: [ICON_FOOD]식량 +1[NEWLINE][ICON_RES_BANANA] 바나나: [ICON_FOOD]식량 +1[NEWLINE][ICON_RES_DEER] 사슴: [ICON_FOOD]식량 +1[NEWLINE][ICON_RES_BISON] 들소: [ICON_FOOD]식량 +1[NEWLINE][ICON_RES_COW] 소: [ICON_FOOD]식량 +1[NEWLINE][ICON_RES_SHEEP] 양: [ICON_FOOD]식량 +1[NEWLINE][ICON_RES_HORSE] 말: [ICON_FOOD]식량 +1</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_YURT_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Unique Mongolian replacement for the Granary. In addition to the Granary's bonuses, the Ger provides Food from livestock. It also provides a small amount of Faith, and has no maintenance. Build Gers in your cities to maximize their growth, and to get an early Pantheon.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_THEMING_BONUS_BUILDING_PARTHENON">
			<Text>고대의 전당</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_THEMING_BONUS_BUILDING_NOTRE_DAME">
			<Text>성역</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PARTHENON_THEMING_BONUS_HELP">
			<Text>보너스를 극대화 하려면 모든 걸작 슬롯을 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]당신 문명[ENDCOLOR]이 만든 [COLOR_YELLOW]유물 또는 예술품[ENDCOLOR]으로 채우십시오.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_NOTRE_DAME_THEMING_BONUS_HELP">
			<Text>보너스를 극대화 하려면 모든 걸작 슬롯을 당신 문명을 제외한 [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]다른 문명[ENDCOLOR]이 만든 [COLOR_YELLOW]유물 또는 예술품[ENDCOLOR]으로 채우십시오.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_NOTIFICATION_PROJECT_STARTED">
			<Text>{1_Player}{1: plural 1?이; 2?가;} [COLOR_NEGATIVE_TEXT]{2_Building}[ENDCOLOR]의 건설을 시작했습니다. [COLOR_NEGATIVE_TEXT]{3_Turns}[ENDCOLOR]턴 뒤에 완성될 예정입니다! 건물이 완성되면 {1_Player}{1: plural 1?은; 2?는;} [COLOR_NEGATIVE_TEXT]문화 승리[ENDCOLOR]를 달성하게 됩니다!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_NOTIFICATION_PROJECT_STARTED_S">
			<Text>[COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]{1_Building}[ENDCOLOR]{1: plural 1?을; 2?를;} 건설 중입니다!</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_ko_KR>
</GameData>
